<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
  <module name="scrtdd" category="Processing" inherit-global-bindings="false">
    <description>
      Double-Difference location module for real-time and event catalogs.
    </description>
    <configuration>
      <parameter name="automaticOrigins" type="boolean" default="true">
        <description>Allow relocation of automatic origins</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="manualOrigins" type="boolean" default="true">
        <description>Allow relocation of manual origins</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="onlyPreferredOrigins" type="boolean" default="true">
        <description>Relocate only preferred origins. When disabled scrtdd listens to LOCATION group and tries to relocate any origin. When enabled scrtdd listens to EVENT group and tries to relocate the preferred origin of an event.</description>
      </parameter>
      <parameter name="activeProfiles" type="list:string" default="">
        <description>Defines a list of active profiles for single-event processing.</description>
      </parameter>
      <group name="performance">
        <parameter name="delayTime" type="int" default="10" unit="sec">
          <description>Specifies a delay time in seconds after an origin is created/updated to trigger the single-event relocation.</description>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="profileTimeAlive" type="int" default="600" unit="sec">
          <description>Defines how long the profile data should be kept in memory (in seconds). This is useful to release memory (catalog waveform data) after a period of inactivity. A negative value force the profiles to stay always in memory.</description>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="cacheWaveforms" type="boolean" default="true">
          <description>Save reference catalog waveforms to local disk after they have been loaded the first time. This avoids re-reading them from the configured recordStream.</description>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="cacheDirectory" type="path" default="@ROOTDIR@/var/lib/rtdd">
          <description>Defines the directory used for storing waveform cache.</description>
        </parameter>
        <parameter name="cachedWaveformLength" type="double" default="10" unit="sec">
          <description>The waveform length (centered around pick time) to be used for the disk cache. Although the required waveform length is inferred from the cross-correlation settings, this option allows for a longer disk cached trace that becomes useful in case the cross-correlation settings are changed in the future.
          </description>
        </parameter> 
      </group>
      <group name="profile">
        <description>Each profile is a configuration set with an optional region. The region is used only in real-time processing to select a profile for an origin. If an origin falls in multiple profile regions, the profile defined first in 'activeProfile' option will be used. This allows for hierarchical regions, where special regions are defined first and a broader region is defined last. A profile is enabled in real-time processing only when added to 'activeProfile' option.</description>
        <struct type="rtdd profile" link="rtdd.activeProfiles">
          <parameter name="regionType" type="string" default="CIRCULAR">
            <description>Type of region: RECTANGULAR or CIRCULAR.</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="region" type="list:double">
            <description>Optional. If regionType is RECTANGULAR then 4 comma separated values are expected: min_lat, min_lon, max_lat, max_lon. If regionType is CIRCULAR then 3 comma separated values are expected: lat, lon, radius in km. If left empty it represents a limitless region.</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="methodID" type="string" default="RTDD">
            <description>This is the methodID label that is stored in the created origin.</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="tableType" type="string" default="LOCSAT">
            <description>Travel time table format type (e.g. LOCSAT, libtau, homogeneous).</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="tableModel" type="string" default="iasp91">
            <description>The model to be used. The format depends on tableType.</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="PSTableOnly" type="boolean" default="true">
            <description>
            If enabled, the arrival travel time information are fetched using 'P' and 'S' tables only and the user selected specific phase type is not considered (e.g. Pg, Sg, PmP, SmS, P1, S1, etc).
          </description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="P-Phases" type="list:string" default="P,Pg,Pn">
            <description>Defines a list of accepted P phases. Phases not in the list will be ignored.</description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="S-Phases" type="list:string" default="S,Sg,Sn">
            <description>Defines a list of accepted S phases. Phases not in the list will be ignored. </description>
          </parameter>
          <parameter name="pickUncertaintyClasses" type="list:string" unit="s" default="0.000,0.025,0.050,0.100,0.200,0.400" >
            <description>Define the pick time uncertainty classes from which the pick weight is computed. This parameter defines a list of uncertainty time intervals: the interval in which a pick time uncertainty falls defines the pick class e.g. a pick with uncertainty of 0.150 falls in the 4th interval and the pick class is then 4. if pick uncertainties are absent, the lowest class will be used. The pick weight is computed as: 1 / 2^(class-1) </description>
          </parameter>
          <group name="catalog">
            <description>Define the reference catalog for single-event mode.</description>
            <parameter name="eventFile" type="path">
              <description>Path to event file to be used for this profile. If this file contains just one column called "origin", then each line must be an existing origin id and neither phase.csv nor station.csv files are required. Alternatively the extended format requires all of event.csv, phase.csv and station.csv files to be provided</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="phaFile" type="path">
              <description>Path to catalog picks file to be used for this profile</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="stationFile" type="path">
              <description>Path to the stations file to be used for this profile</description>
            </parameter>
          </group>
          <group name="doubleDifferenceSystem">
            <description>These options control the clustering phase, which is responsible to selects the event pairs and their phases to be used in the double-difference equation system.</description> 
            <group name="eventFiltering">
              <description>Exclude poorly connected events from the DD system: not enough phases and/or neighbours</description>
              <parameter name="minNumPhases" type="int" default="4">
                <description>Minimum number of phases at common stations required by event pairs. Event pairs not satisfying this condition will not be used.</description>
              </parameter> 
              <parameter name="minNumNeighbours" type="int" default="4">
                <description>Minimum number of neighbours required by an event. Events not satisfying this condition will not be used.</description>
              </parameter>
            </group>
            <group name="phaseFiltering">
              <description>Exclude not optimal phases from the DD system.</description>
              <parameter name="minStationToEventPairDistRatio" type="double" default="1">
                <description>Minimum ratio between event-station to inter-event distance allowed. Phases belonging to stations not satisfying this condition will not be used.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="minStationDistance" type="double" unit="km">
                <description>Minimum distance (km) between event and station required for a phase to be used. Phases belonging to stations not satisfying this condition will not be used.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="maxStationDistance" type="double" unit="km">
                <description>Max distance (km) between event and station allowed for a phase to be used. Phases belonging to stations not satisfying this condition will not be used. A value of 0 or less disables this limit.</description>
              </parameter>
            </group>
            <group name="eventPairSelection">
              <description>Control how neighbouring events are selected. In the simpliest form 'numEllipsoids' is set to 0 and the neighbours are selected on the nearest neighbour basis within a search distance of 'maxNeighbourDistance'. When 'numEllipsoids' is not 0, the ellipsoid selection algorithm is used. From Waldhauser 2009: "to assure a spatially homogeneous subsampling, reference events are selected within each of five concentric, vertically elongated ellipsoidal layers of increasing thickness. The dimension of the ellipsoid is based on the assumed error in the routine locations and the maximum interevent distance over which model errors can still be effectively minimized. The layers are twice as thick at the poles than they are at the equator to accommodate the generally larger error in the depth of the routine location of a new event. Each layer is split up into its eight quadrants (or cells), and the neighboring events are selected from each of the 40 cells.". Thus the neighbours are selected for each ellipsoid/quadrant combination in a round robin fashion until 'maxNumNeighbours' is reached.</description>
              <group name="singleEvent">
                <description>Configuration for single-event relocation</description>
                <parameter name="maxNumNeighbours" type="int" default="80">
                  <description>Maximum number of neighbors per event. A value of 0 disables this limit</description>
                </parameter>
                <parameter name="maxNeighbourDistance" type="double" default="5" unit="km">
                  <description>Maximum distance allowed between an event and its neighbouring events. if numEllipsoids is greater than 0, then this value is the horizontal axes length (km) of the outermost boundary. Each inner concentric layer axis will be half of the previous one. The vertical axis is twice as long as the horizontal ones.</description>
                </parameter>
                <parameter name="numEllipsoids" type="int" default="5">
                  <description>If set to 0 the nearest neighbour event selection is used. Otherwise this is the number of concentric ellipsoidal layers to be used in the neighboring event selection.</description>
                </parameter>
              </group>
              <group name="multiEvent">
                <description>Configuration for multi-event relocation</description>
                <parameter name="maxNumNeighbours" type="int" default="40">
                  <description>Maximum number of neighbors per event. A value of 0 or less disables this limit</description>
                </parameter>
                <parameter name="maxNeighbourDistance" type="double" default="5" unit="km">
                  <description>Maximum distance allowed between an event and its neighbouring events. if numEllipsoids is greater than 0, then this value is the horizontal axes length (km) of the outermost boundary. Each inner concentric layer axis will be half of the previous one. The vertical axis is twice as long as the horizontal ones.</description>
                </parameter>
                <parameter name="numEllipsoids" type="int" default="0">
                  <description>If set to 0 the nearest neighbour event selection is used. Otherwise this is the number of concentric ellipsoidal layers to be used in the neighboring event selection.</description>
                </parameter>
              </group>
            </group>
          </group>
          <group name="crossCorrelation">
            <description>Cross-correlation is used to improve the differential times used in the double-difference system</description>
            <parameter name="enable" type="boolean" default="false">
              <description>Enable or disable the waveform cross-correlation.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="minStationDistance" type="double" default="0" unit="km">
              <description>Minimum allowed distance between event and station. Phases belonging to closer stations will not be used in cross-correlation.</description> 
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="maxStationDistance" type="double" default="60" unit="km">
              <description>Maximum allowed distance between event and station. Phases belonging to further stations will not be used in cross-correlation. Setting it to -1 removes the limits.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="maxInterEventDistance" type="double" default="2" unit="km">
              <description>Maximum allowed distance (km) between events for a cross-correlation to happen. Phases of event pairs whose inter-event distance if further than this value will not be used in cross-correlation. Setting it to -1 removes the limits.</description>
            </parameter>
            <group name="p-phase">
              <parameter name="minCCCoef" type="double" default="0.70">
                <description>Min cross-correlation coefficient accepted to use a differential travel time.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winStart" type="double" default="-0.50" unit="sec">
                <description>Start of data window to cross-correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winEnd" type="double" default="0.50" unit="sec">
                <description>End of data window to cross-correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winScaling" type="double" default="0.02">
                <description>Window scaling coefficient. Window Length = (winEnd-winStart) + TravelTime * winScaling.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="maxDelay" type="double" default="0.50" unit="sec">
                <description>Maximum data windows lag accepted (secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="components" type="list:string" default="Z">
                <description>Priority list of components to be used in the cross-correlation (e.g. Z, N, E, 1, 2, 3). If the component exists for both the phases to be cross-correlated then it is used, otherwise the next component in the list is tried. Special values are 'H', which computes the L2 norm of the 2 horizontal components and 'T' (and 'R'), which computes the transversal (and radial) component with respect with the event location to which the phase belongs to. If the value is left empty, the component where the phases were picked is used (if identical).</description>
              </parameter>
            </group>
            <group name="s-phase">
              <parameter name="minCCCoef" type="double" default="0.70">
                <description>Min cross-correlation coefficient accepted to use a differential travel time.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winStart" type="double" default="-0.50" unit="sec">
                <description>Start of data window to cross-correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winEnd" type="double" default="1.00" unit="sec">
                <description>End of data window to cross-correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="winScaling" type="double" default="0.04">
                <description>Window scaling coefficient. Window Length = (winEnd-winStart) + TravelTime * winScaling.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="maxDelay" type="double" default="0.50" unit="sec">
                <description>Maximum data windows lag accepted (secs).</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="components" type="list:string" default="H">
                <description>Priority list of components to be used in the cross-correlation (e.g. Z, N, E, 1, 2, 3). If the component exists for both the phases to be cross-correlated then it is used, otherwise the next component in the list is tried. Special values are 'H', which computes the L2 norm of the 2 horizontal components and 'T' (and 'R'), which computes the transversal (and radial) component with respect with the event location to which the phase belongs to. If the value is left empty, the component where the phases were picked is used (if identical).</description>
              </parameter>
            </group>
            <group name="waveformFiltering">
              <description>Filter waveforms before performing the cross-correlation</description>
              <parameter name="filterString" type="string" default="">
                <description>SeisComP string based filter definition e.g."ITAPER(1)>>BW_HLP(2,1,20)". Set to "" to disable filtering.</description>
              </parameter>
              <parameter name="margin" type="double" default="1" unit="sec">
                <description>Extra seconds to add to the waveform ends before applying the filter. Useful to initialize the filter and to discard potential filter artifacts at the beginning and end of trace</description>
              </parameter> 
              <parameter name="resampling" type="double" default="0" unit="Hz">
                <description>Resample all traces at this samplig interval (hz) Set it to 0 disable resampling.</description>
              </parameter>
            </group>
          </group>
          <group name="solver">
            <description>These options control the double-difference system solver. The solution to the double-difference system is found through an iterative process: a double-difference system is built from the origin initial locations and solved. Then the hypocenters are updated based on these initial solutions and a new system is built and solved again multiple times until 'algoIterations' iterations is reached.</description>
            <parameter name="solverType" type="string" default="LSMR">
              <description>Solver algorithm to use: either LSMR or LSQR</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="algoIterations" type="int" default="20">
              <description>Number of iterations for the solver to perform.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="downWeightingByResidual" type="list:double" default="10,5" >
              <description>At each iteration the solver down-weighs the double-difference equations accordingly to their residuals. This option indicates the standard deviation of the residuals beyond which an equation weight becomes 0. A value of 0 disables downweighting. One or two values can be given; when two values are given the first value is used in the first iteration, the second value in the last iteration and the iterations in between use interpolated values.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="dampingFactor" type="list:double" default="0.01" >
              <description>Setting a value different than 0 enables the solver to use a damped (regularized) least squares system. A too high value prevents the solver from changing the events locations, while a too low value allows the event cluster(s) to shift away from their absolute location (unless `absoluteLocationConstraint` is used). One or two values can be given; when two values are given the first value is used in the first iteration, the second value in the last iteration and the iterations in between use interpolated values.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="absoluteLocationConstraint" type="list:double" default="0.3" >
              <description>When a value greater than 0 is used, the double-difference system is modified to solve for both absolute and relative locations. Additional equations are added, which constrain the absolute travel time residuals. This option selects the weight to be given to these equations. One or two values can be given; when two values are given the first value is used in the first iteration, the second value in the last iteration and the iterations in between use interpolated values.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="xcorrWeightScaler" type="double" default="1.5">
              <description>Weight scaling of the equations that use cross-correlation differential times with respect to equations that use differential pick times only.</description>
            </parameter>
            <parameter name="usePickUncertainties" type="boolean" default="false">
              <description>Whether to use pick time uncertainty to weigh each pick accordingly to 'pickUncertaintyClasses'. If enabled, each double-difference equation weight will be the average of its pick weights.</description>
            </parameter>
          </group>
        </struct>
      </group>
    </configuration>
    <command-line>
      <group name="Generic">
        <optionReference>generic#help</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#version</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#config-file</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#plugins</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#daemon</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#auto-shutdown</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#shutdown-master-module</optionReference>
        <optionReference>generic#shutdown-master-username</optionReference>
      </group>
      <group name="Verbosity">
        <optionReference>verbosity#verbosity</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#v</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#quiet</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#component</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#syslog</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#lockfile</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#console</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#debug</optionReference>
        <optionReference>verbosity#log-file</optionReference>
      </group>
      <group name="Messaging">
        <optionReference>messaging#user</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#host</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#timeout</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#primary-group</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#subscribe-group</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#content-type</optionReference>
        <optionReference>messaging#start-stop-msg</optionReference>
      </group>
      <group name="Database">
        <optionReference>database#db-driver-list</optionReference>
        <optionReference>database#database</optionReference>
        <optionReference>database#config-module</optionReference>
        <optionReference>database#inventory-db</optionReference>
        <optionReference>database#db-disable</optionReference>
      </group>
      <group name="Records">
        <optionReference>records#record-driver-list</optionReference>
        <optionReference>records#record-url</optionReference>
        <optionReference>records#record-file</optionReference>
        <optionReference>records#record-type</optionReference>
      </group>
      <group name="Mode">
        <option long-flag="reloc-catalog" argument="profile">
          <description>Relocate the catalog passed as argument in multi-event mode. The input can be a single file (containing seiscomp origin ids) or a file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv). For events stored in a XML file add the --ep option.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="origin-id" flag="O" argument="origin-id">
          <description>Relocate the origin (or multiple comma-separated origins) and send a message. Each origin will be processed according tothe matching profile region unless the --profile option is used.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="ep" argument="scxml-file">
          <description>Event parameters XML file for offline processing of contained origins (implies --test option). Each contained origin will be processed in signle-event mode unless --reloc-catalog is provided, which enable multi-evet mode.</description>
        </option>      
        <option long-flag="eval-xcorr" argument="profile">
          <description>Evaluate cross-correlation settings for the given profile.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="dump-clusters" argument="profile">
          <description>Find clusters in the catalog passed as argument and save them in the working directory. The catalog can be a single file (containing seiscomp origin ids) or a file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv). Use in combination with --profile.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="dump-wf" argument="profile">
          <description>Dump processed waveforms of the catalog passed as argument in the current working directory. The catalog can be a single file (containing seiscomp origin ids) or a file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv). Use in combination with --profile.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="load-profile-wf" argument="profile">
          <description>Load catalog waveforms from the configured recordstream and save them into the profile working directory.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="send-reload-profile-msg">
          <description>Send a message to any running scrtdd module requesting to reload a specific profile passed as argument.</description>
        </option>        
      </group>
      <group name="Catalog">
        <option long-flag="dump-catalog" argument="catalog-file">
          <description>Dump the seiscomp event/origin id file passed as argument into a catalog file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv).</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="dump-catalog-options" argument="type,evalmode,includeCreator,excludeCreator,region">
          <description>Allows the --dump-catalog option to accept event ids besides origin ids. For each event id an origin will be selected following the provided options whose format is: 'type,evalmode,include Creator,excludeCreator,region', where type=preferred|last|first evalmode=any|onlyManual|onlyAutomatic includeCreator=any|author|methodID excludeCreator=none|author|methodID region=any|profileName e.g. to select preferred origins of the input event ids that lie within the region defined for 'myProfile' use 'preferred,any,any,none ,myProfile'</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="merge-catalogs" argument="catalog-files">
          <description>Merge in a single catalog all the catalog file triplets (station1.csv,event1.csv,phase1.csv,sta tion2.csv,event2.csv,phase2.csv,...) passed as arguments.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="merge-catalogs-keepid" argument="catalog-files">
          <description>Similar to the --merge-catalogs option but events keep their ids. If multiple events share the same id, subsequent events will be discarded.</description>
        </option>
      </group>
      <group name="ModeOptions">
        <option long-flag="profile" argument="profile"> 
          <description>To be used in combination with other options: select the profile configuration to use.</description>
        </option>  
        <option long-flag="xmlout">
          <description>Enable XML output when combined with --reloc-catalog or --oring-id options.</description>
        </option> 
        <option long-flag="xcorr-cache">
          <description>Specify a file containing precomputed cross-correlation values.</description>
        </option>       
        <option long-flag="test">
          <description>Test mode, no messages are sent</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="cache-wf-all">
          <description>All waveforms will be saved to disk cache, even temporarily ones. Normally only catalog phase waveforms are cached to disk. This is useful to speed up debugging/testing when the same origins are repeatedly processed.</description>
        </option>
        <option long-flag="expiry" flag="x" argument="hours">
          <description>Defines the time span in hours after which objects expire.</description>
        </option>
      </group>     
    </command-line>
  </module>
</seiscomp>
