<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
    <module name="scrtdd" category="Processing" inherit-global-bindings="true">
        <description>Real Time Double-Difference location module.</description>
        <configuration>

            <parameter name="publicIDpattern" type="string" default="RTDD.@time/%Y%m%d%H%M%S.%f@.@id@">
                <description>
                    PublicID creation pattern for an origin created by RTDD.
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <parameter name="onlyPreferredOrigins" type="boolean" default="true">
                <description>
                    Relocate only preferred origins. Without this option scrtdd listens to LOCATION and
                    try to relocate any origin. If this option is set scrtdd listens to EVENT and
                    try to relcoate the preferred origin of an event.
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <parameter name="manualOrigins" type="boolean" default="false">
                <description>
                    If disable manual origins are not relocated.
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <parameter name="workingDirectory" type="path" default="@ROOTDIR@/var/lib/rtdd">
                <description>
                    Defines the directory used for storing processing files (waveforms cache
                    and debugging files).
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <parameter name="keepWorkingFiles" type="boolean" default="false">
                <description>
                    Do not delete temporary processing files from the working directory
                    after the processing is completed (useful for debugging only).
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <parameter name="activeProfiles" type="list:string" default="">
                <description>
                    Defines a list of active profiles.
                </description>
            </parameter>

            <group name="performance">

                <parameter name="profileTimeAlive" type="int" default="-1">
                    <description>
                        Defines how long the profile data should be kept in memory (in seconds). This is useful
                        to release memory (e.g. catalog waveform data) after a period of inactivity at the cost of
                        re-loading and re-process the waveforms whenever a new event occurs (not 
                        very time consuming but still a bit slower than keeping the waveforms in memory).
                        A negative value force the profile to never expires (always in memory).
                    </description>
                </parameter>

                <parameter name="cacheWaveforms" type="boolean" default="true">
                    <description>
                        Save catalog waveforms to local disk to avoid re-reading them from the configured
                        recordStream when a profile is loaded (see profileTimeAlive).
                        The waveforms are saved in the configured working directory and they can also be
                        moved to other machines. Also it is safe to delete the
                        cache, in which case the waveforms will be loaded and saved again on disk
                        the next time the profile is loaded (they will be read again from the configured
                        recordStream).
                        Please note that exists a command line options '--load-profile-wf' useful to load
                        the catalog waveforms from the record stream and save them on disk. This is useful
                        to make sure all the data is ready when the module is started and avoid lenghty
                        loading in case of big catalogs or slow network connection.
                    </description>
                </parameter>

        </group>

            <group name="cron">

                <parameter name="wakeupInterval" type="int" unit="s" default="5">
                    <description>
                        Specifies the interval in seconds to check/start scheduled operations.
                        This is basically the time resolution for delayTimes option.
                    </description>
                </parameter>

                <parameter name="delayTimes" type="list:int" default="60,120,300,600,3600">
                    <description>
                    Specifies a delay time in seconds, relative to origin time,
                    to trigger the processing. This can be a single value or a list of delay
                    times. The list case can be useful when a quick solution is wanted but
                    more data (e.g. waveforms) becomes available at a later time. In this
                    scenario multiple times are configured so that an early solution is attempted
                    and a more refined one is computed later.
                    Example: &quot;60, 120, 300, 3600&quot;
                    </description>
                </parameter>

                <parameter name="logging" type="boolean" default="true">
                    <description>
                    Enables/disables updating of a cron log file. This file will be
                    created at ~/.seiscomp3/log/[appname].sched
                    and contains information about the scheduled events and the
                    processing queue. The file is updated each n seconds,
                    where n = rtdd.cron.wakeupInterval.
                    </description>
                </parameter>

            </group>

            <group name="profile">
                <struct type="rtdd profile" link = "rtdd.activeProfiles">
                    <description>
                        Defines a regional profile. Origins that fall in this region will use this
                        configuration. If an origin falls in multiple profile regions, then the
                        profile defined first in activeProfile option will be used.
                        This hierarchical regions, where a generic and broad region is defined as last
                        entry to be used as last resort default region and more specifig and small 
                        regions are defined first to be used for specic areas with custom settings.
                        The region check is not used for full catalog relocation (see --relocate-profile
                        command line option)
                    </description>

                    <parameter name="regionType" type="string">
                        <description>
                            Type of region: RECTANGULAR or CIRCULAR
                        </description>
                    </parameter>

                    <parameter name="region" type="list:double">
                        <description>
                            Defines the region values. If regionType is RECTANGULAR then 4 values
                            (min_lat, min_lon, max_lat, max_lon) are expected. If regionType
                            is CIRCULAR then 3 values are expected (lat, lon, radius in km).
                            If region is empty, then it will represent a region that matches any
                            origin.
                        </description>
                    </parameter>

                    <parameter name="earthModelID" type="string">
                        <description>
                            earthModelID that is stored in the created origin.
                        </description>
                    </parameter>

                    <parameter name="methodID" type="string" default="RTDD">
                        <description>
                            methodID that is stored in the created origin.
                        </description>
                    </parameter>

                    <group name="catalog">
                        <description>
                            The files used to define a background catalog. New origins will be relocated using this
                            catalog, which must contains high quality locations. In full catalog relocation mode
                            (see --relocate-profile command line option) this is the catalog that will be relocated.
                            There are two ways to define a catalog: one is providing an event file containing the ids
                            of existing origins; the second way consists in providing extended information 
                            (useful when the events are not in the database) and three files are required event, phase
                            and stations.
                            The files must be in csv format with the first line containing the column names. Each file
                            requires a minimum set of columns, which can appear in any order. Additional
                            columns can be present and will not be used but are allowed.
                        </description>

                        <parameter name="eventFile" type="path">
                            <description>
                                Path to event file to be used for this profile.
                                Seiscomp format required columns: seiscompId (this must be a valide seiscomp3 origin id)
                                Extended format columns: id,isotime,latitude,longitude,depth,magnitude,horiz_err,depth_err,tt_residual
                                If the extended format is used, then the phase and station files must be provided.
                                Conversely, if the format used is the one with seiscompId, no other files have to be
                                provided and the event information will be fetched from the database.
                            </description>
                        </parameter>

                        <parameter name="phaFile" type="path">
                            <description>
                                Path to catalog picks file to be used for this profile 
                                Columns: eventId,stationId,isotime,lowerUncertainty,upperUncertainty,type,networkCode,stationCode,locationCode,channelCode,evalMode
                            </description>
                        </parameter>

                        <parameter name="stationFile" type="path">
                            <description>
                                Path to the stations file to be used for this profile
                                Columns: id,latitude,longitude,elevation,networkCode,stationCode,locationCode
                            </description>
                        </parameter>

                        <parameter name="P-Phases" type="list:string" default="Pg,P,Px">
                            <description>
                                Defines a priority list of accepted P phases. Phases not in the list will be discarded.
                                if multiple phases exist for the same event/station pair, the first one in the list will be used.
                            </description>
                        </parameter>

                        <parameter name="S-Phases" type="list:string" default="Sg,S,Sx">
                            <description>
                                Defines a priority list of accepted S phases. Phases not in this list will be discarded.
                                if multiple phases exist for the same event/station pair, the first one in the list will be used.
                            </description>
                        </parameter>

                    </group>

                    <group name="step1options">
                        <description>
                            These options control the step 1 of real-time single event relocation. These options
                            are NOT used in multi-event (full catalog) relocation (--relocate-profile command
                            line option).
                            The real-time relocation works in two steps: the first one is the location refinement,
                            in which scrtdd compute a preliminary relocation of the origin using only catalog
                            absolute travel times (dt.ct) and it is controlled by those options. A second step 
                            relocation is then performed, where scrtdd use both catalog absolute travel times (dt.ct)
                            and cross correlation differential travel times (dt.cc) for pairs of earthquakes, which
                            is controlled by step2options.
                            The multi-event (full catalog) relocation works in one step only, where the relocation
                            is performed with both catalog absolute travel times (dt.ct) and cross correlation
                            differential travel times (dt.cc),  both controlled by step2options.
                        </description>
                        <group name="clustering">
                            <description>
                                Those options control the creation of catalog absolute travel time entries
                                (dt.ct file in HypoDD terminology) and cross correlation differential travel times
                                (dt.cc file in HypoDD terminology) for pairs of earthquakes. To build the event
                                pairs a clustering algorithm is performed, joining together events that have phases
                                on same stations. Here it is possible to configure how the clustering is performed,
                                selecting how/what events and phases will be used.
                            </description>
                            <parameter name="minNumNeigh" type="int">
                                <description>
                                    Min number of neighboring events required to relocate an event. Disabled by
                                    default.
                                    This is useful to avoid including solutions that are poorly constrained.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="maxNumNeigh" type="int">
                                <description>
                                    Max number of neighbors per event. No limit by default. When setting this
                                    value make it consistent with numEllipsoids parameter (that is 
                                    numEllipsoids * 8) if numEllipsoids is not 0
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="minObservationPerEvtPair" type="int" >
                                <description>
                                    Min number of differential travel times (Including P+S) per event pair required.
                                    Event pairs not satisfying this condition will not be used.
                                    Check disabled by default.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="maxObservationPerEvtPair" type="int" >
                                <description>
                                    Max number of differential travel times (Including P+S) per event pair used.
                                    If this value is set, closer stations will have higher precedence over further
                                    ones. No limit by default.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <group name="neighboringEventSelection">
                                <description>
                                    This option define how neighbouring events are selected.
                                    From Waldhauser 2009: "to assure a spatially homogeneous subsampling, reference
                                    events are selected within each of five concentric, vertically elongated
                                    ellipsoidal layers of increasing thickness.
                                    The dimension of the ellipsoid is based on the assumed error in the routine
                                    locations and the maximum interevent distance over which model errors can still
                                    be effectively minimized (see Waldhauser, 2001).
                                    The layers are twice as thick at the poles than they are at the equator to 
                                    accommodate the generally larger error in the depth of the routine location of
                                    a new event. Each layer is split up into its eight quadrants (or cells), and 
                                    the  neighboring events are selected from each of the 40 cells."
                                    SCRTDD selects neighbours for each ellipsoid/quadrant conbination in
                                    a round robin fashion until "maxNumNeigh" is reached. If there are no events
                                    in a specific ellipsoid/quadrant location it is simply skipped.
                                    Note: if numEllipsoids is 0 then the concentric ellipsoid algorithm will not
                                    be used and the events will be selected on nearest neighbor basis within a
                                    search distance of maxEllipsoidSize. This is useful when performing multi-event
                                    relocation to build a background catalog where we seek a network of links between
                                    events so that there exists a chain of pairwise connected events from any one
                                    event to any other event, with the distance being as small as possible between
                                    connected events
                                </description>
                                <parameter name="numEllipsoids" type="int" default="5">
                                    <description>
                                        Number of concentric ellipsoidal layers to use in neighboring events 
                                        selection. if maxNumNeigh is not set this parameter does not have effects.
                                        If maxNumNeigh is used, make it consistent with numEllipsoids 
                                        (numEllipsoids * 8) if numEllipsoids is not 0
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxEllipsoidSize" type="double" default="5">
                                    <description>
                                        Horizontal axis length (km) of the outermost boundary. Each inner
                                        concentric layer axis will be of size/2 of the previous one. Please note
                                        that the horizontal axis size is half of the vertical one.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter> 
                            </group>
                            <group name="phaseSelection">
                                <description>
                                    This option define how event phases are selected. 
                                </description>
                                <parameter name="minStationDistance" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min distance (km) between event pair and station required. Phases belonging
                                        to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        Check disabled by default. 
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxStationDistance" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Max distance (km) between event pair and station allowed. Phases belonging
                                        to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        No limit by default.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="minStaionToEventPairDistRatio" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min ratio between event-station distance and pair inter-event-pair distance. Phases
                                        belonging to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        Check disabled by default.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter> 
                            </group> 
                        </group> 
                    </group>

                    <group name="step2options">
                        <description>
                            These options control the step 2 of real-time single event relocation and the
                            multi-event (full catalog) relocation (--relocate-profile command line option).
                            The real-time relocation works in two steps: the first one is the location refinement,
                            in which scrtdd compute a preliminary relocation of the origin using only catalog
                            absolute travel times (dt.ct), and a second step relocation (controlled by these options),
                            where scrtdd  performs a more precise relocation using both catalog absolute 
                            travel times (dt.ct) and cross correlation differential travel times (dt.cc) for pairs 
                            of earthquakes.
                            The multi-event (full catalog) relocation works in one step only, where the relocation
                            is performed with both catalog absolute travel times (dt.ct) and cross correlation
                            differential travel times (dt.cc),  both controlled by step2options. 
                        </description>
                        <group name="clustering">
                            <description>
                                Those options control the creation of catalog absolute travel time entries
                                (dt.ct file in HypoDD terminology) and cross correlation differential travel times
                                (dt.cc file in HypoDD terminology) for pairs of earthquakes. To build the event
                                pairs a clustering algorithm is performed, joining together events that have phases
                                on same stations. Here it is possible to configure how the clustering is performed,
                                selecting how/what events and phases will be used.
                            </description>
                            <parameter name="minNumNeigh" type="int">
                                <description>
                                    Min number of neighboring events required to relocate an event. Disabled by
                                    default.
                                    This is useful to avoid including solutions that are poorly constrained.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="maxNumNeigh" type="int">
                                <description>
                                    Max number of neighbors per event. No limit by default. When setting this
                                    value make it consistent with numEllipsoids parameter (that is 
                                    numEllipsoids * 8) if numEllipsoids is not 0
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="minObservationPerEvtPair" type="int" >
                                <description>
                                    Min number of differential travel times (Including P+S) per event pair required.
                                    Event pairs not satisfying this condition will not be used.
                                    Check disabled by default.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="maxObservationPerEvtPair" type="int" >
                                <description>
                                    Max number of differential travel times (Including P+S) per event pair used.
                                    If this value is set, closer stations will have higher precedence over further
                                    ones. No limit by default.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <group name="neighboringEventSelection">
                                <description>
                                    This option define how neighbouring events are selected.
                                    From Waldhauser 2009: "to assure a spatially homogeneous subsampling, reference
                                    events are selected within each of five concentric, vertically elongated
                                    ellipsoidal layers of increasing thickness.
                                    The dimension of the ellipsoid is based on the assumed error in the routine
                                    locations and the maximum interevent distance over which model errors can still
                                    be effectively minimized (see Waldhauser, 2001).
                                    The layers are twice as thick at the poles than they are at the equator to 
                                    accommodate the generally larger error in the depth of the routine location of
                                    a new event. Each layer is split up into its eight quadrants (or cells), and 
                                    the  neighboring events are selected from each of the 40 cells."
                                    SCRTDD selects neighbours for each ellipsoid/quadrant conbination in
                                    a round robin fashion until "maxNumNeigh" is reached. If there are no events
                                    in a specific ellipsoid/quadrant location it is simply skipped.
                                    Note: if numEllipsoids is 0 then the concentric ellipsoid algorithm will not
                                    be used and the events will be selected on nearest neighbor basis within a
                                    search distance of maxEllipsoidSize. This is useful when performing multi-event
                                    relocation to build a background catalog where we seek a network of links between
                                    events so that there exists a chain of pairwise connected events from any one
                                    event to any other event, with the distance being as small as possible between
                                    connected events
                                </description>
                                <parameter name="numEllipsoids" type="int" default="5">
                                    <description>
                                        Number of concentric ellipsoidal layers to use in neighboring events 
                                        selection. if maxNumNeigh is not set this parameter does not have effects.
                                        If maxNumNeigh is used, make it consistent with numEllipsoids (numEllipsoids * 8) if numEllipsoids is not 0
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxEllipsoidSize" type="double" default="5">
                                    <description>
                                        Horizontal axis length (km) of the outermost boundary. Each inner
                                        concentric layer axis will be of size/2 of the previous one. Please note
                                        that the horizontal axis size is half of the vertical one.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter> 
                            </group>
                            <group name="phaseSelection">
                                <description>
                                    This option define how event phases are selected. 
                                </description>
                                <parameter name="minStationDistance" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min distance (km) between event pair and station required. Phases belonging
                                        to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        Check disabled by default. 
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxStationDistance" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Max distance (km) between event pair and station allowed. Phases belonging
                                        to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        No limit by default.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="minStaionToEventPairDistanceRatio" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min ratio between event-station distance and pair inter-event-pair distance. Phases
                                        belonging to stations not satisfyig this condition will not be used.
                                        Check disabled by default.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter> 
                            </group>
                        </group>

                        <group name="crosscorrelation">
                            <group name="p-phase">
                                <parameter name="minCCCoef" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min crosscorrelation coefficient accepted to use a differential travel time
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="start" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Start of data window to cross correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs)
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="end" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        End of data window to cross correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs)
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxDelay" type="double">
                                    <description>Maximum data windows lag accepted (secs)</description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="components" type="list:string" default="Z">
                                    <description>
                                        Priority list of components to be used in cross-correlation.
                                        If cross-correlation is below threshold on a component, the next
                                        component is tried.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                            </group>
                            <group name="s-phase">
                                <parameter name="minCCCoef" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Min crosscorrelation coefficient accepted to use a differential travel time
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="start" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        Start of data window to cross correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs)
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="end" type="double">
                                    <description>
                                        End of data window to cross correlate with respect to pick time (+/- secs)
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="maxDelay" type="double">
                                    <description>Maximum data windows lag accepted (secs)</description>
                                </parameter>
                                <parameter name="components" type="list:string" default="T,Z">
                                    <description>
                                        Priority list of components to be used in cross-correlation.
                                        If cross-correlation is below threshold on a component, the next
                                        component is tried.
                                    </description>
                                </parameter>
                            </group>
                        </group>

                        <group name="waveformFiltering">
                            <description>
                                Filter waveforms before performing the cross correlation
                            </description>
                            <parameter name="filterString" type="string">
                                <description>SeisComP3 string based filter definition</description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="resampling" type="double">
                                <description>
                                    Resample all traces at this samplig interval (hz)
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                        </group>

                        <group name="snr">
                           <description>
                               Exclude phases from cross correlation when Signal to Noise Ratio is below
                               a configured threshold.
                           </description>
                           <parameter name="minSnr" type="double">
                                <description>
                                    Minimum Signal to Noise Ratio value required to use a Pick in cross correlation.
                                    If minSnr is used, then the noise and signal windows must be defined too.
                                </description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="noiseStart" type="double">
                                <description>Start of noise  window with respect to pick time (+/- secs)</description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="noiseEnd" type="double">
                                <description>End of noise  window with respect to pick time (+/- secs)</description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="signalStart" type="double">
                                <description>Start of signal window with respect to pick time (+/- secs)</description>
                            </parameter>
                            <parameter name="signalEnd" type="double">
                                <description>End of signal window with respect to pick time (+/- secs)</description>
                            </parameter> 
                        </group>
                    </group>

                    <group name="solver">
                        <description>
                            Configuration for the double-difference equations system
                       </description>
                        <parameter name="tableType" type="string" default="LOCSAT">
                            <description>i
                                Type of traveltime tables to use. e.g. libtau or LOCSAT
                            </description>
                        </parameter>
                        <parameter name="tableModel" type="string" default="iasp91">
                            <description>
                                Traveltime table model to use. This can be a system default
                                or a user defined one. Either way, it has to be configured
                                in global settings and selected in here.
                            </description>
                        </parameter>   
                        <parameter name="solverType" type="string" default="LSMR" >
                            <description>
                                Solver algorithm to use: either LSMR or LSQR
                            </description>
                        </parameter>   
                        <parameter name="dampingFactor" type="double" default="0">
                            <description>
                            </description>
                        </parameter>
                        <parameter name="useObservationWeights" type="boolean" default="true">
                            <description>
                            </description>
                        </parameter> 
                    </group>
 
                </struct>
            </group>

        </configuration>
        <command-line>
            <group name="Generic">
                <optionReference>generic#help</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#version</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#config-file</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#plugins</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#daemon</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#auto-shutdown</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#shutdown-master-module</optionReference>
                <optionReference>generic#shutdown-master-username</optionReference>
            </group>
            
            <group name="Verbosity">
                <optionReference>verbosity#verbosity</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#v</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#quiet</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#component</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#syslog</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#lockfile</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#console</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#debug</optionReference>
                <optionReference>verbosity#log-file</optionReference>
            </group>
            
            <group name="Messaging">
                <optionReference>messaging#user</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#host</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#timeout</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#primary-group</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#subscribe-group</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#encoding</optionReference>
                <optionReference>messaging#start-stop-msg</optionReference>
            </group>

            <group name="Database">
                <optionReference>database#db-driver-list</optionReference>
                <optionReference>database#database</optionReference>
                <optionReference>database#config-module</optionReference>
                <optionReference>database#inventory-db</optionReference>
                <optionReference>database#db-disable</optionReference>
            </group>

            <group name="Records">
                <optionReference>records#record-driver-list</optionReference>
                <optionReference>records#record-url</optionReference>
                <optionReference>records#record-file</optionReference>
                <optionReference>records#record-type</optionReference>
            </group>

            <group name="Mode">

                <option long-flag="load-profile-wf" argument="profile">
                    <description>Load catalog waveforms from the configured recordstream and save them in the working directory configured for the profile</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="debug-wf">
                    <description>Enable the dumping of waveforms (filtered and resampled phases, artificial phases, SNR rejected phases) into the profile working directory ('cacheWaveforms' folder). Useful when run in combination with --load-profile-wf</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="debug-wf-cache">
                    <description>
                        All waveforms will be saved to disk cache, this is useful to speed up debugging/testing. Normally only catalog phase waveforms are cached to disk since they are re-used.
                    </description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="eval-xcorr" argument="profile">
                    <description>"Evaluate cross-correlation settings for the given profile</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="expiry" flag="x" argument="hours">
                    <description>Time span in hours after which objects expire</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="dump-config">
                    <description>Dump the configuration and exit</description>
                </option>

            </group>
            <group name="Catalog">

                <option long-flag="dump-catalog" argument="catalog-file">
                    <description>Dump the seiscomp event/origin id file passed as argument into a catalog file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv)</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="dump-catalog-options" argument="type,evalmode,includeCreator,excludeCreator,region">
                    <description>Allows --dump-catalog to accept event ids besides origin ids. For each event id an origin will be selected following the provided options whose format is: 'type,evalmode,includeCreator,excludeCreator,region', where type=preferred|last|first  evalmode=any|onlyManual|onlyAutomatic  includeCreator=any|author|methodID  excludeCreator=none|author|methodID  region=any|profileName e.g. to select preferred origins within my profile region given the input event ids use 'preferred,any,any,none,myProfile'
                    </description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="dump-catalog-xml" argument="catalog-files">
                    <description>Convert the input catalog into XML format. The input can be a single file (containing seiscomp event/origin ids) or a catalog file triplet (station.csv,event.csv,phase.csv)</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="merge-catalogs" argument="catalog-files">
                    <description>Merge in a single catalog all the catalog file triplets (station1.csv,event1.csv,phase1.csv,station2.csv,event2.csv,phase2.csv,...) passed as arguments.</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="merge-catalogs-keepid" argument="catalog-files">
                    <description>Similar to --merge-catalogs option but events keeps their ids. If multiple events share the same id, subsequent events will be discarded.</description>
                </option>

            </group>
            <group name="SingleEvent">

                <option long-flag="origin-id" flag="O" argument="origin-id">
                    <description>Relocate the origin (or multiple comma-separated origins) and send a message. Each origin will be processed accordingly with the matching profile region unless --profile option is used</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="ep" argument="xml-file">
                    <description>Event parameters XML file for offline processing of contained origins (imply test option). Each origin will be processed accordingly with the matching profile region unless --profile option is used</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="test">
                    <description>"Test mode, no messages are sent</description>
                </option>

                <option long-flag="profile" argument="profile">
                    <description>
                        Force a specific profile to be used when relocating an origin. This overrides the selection 
                        of profiles based on region information and the initial origin location
                    </description>
                </option>

            </group>

            <group name="MultiEvents">

                <option long-flag="reloc-profile" argument="profile">
                    <description>Relocate the catalog of profile passed as argument</description>
                </option>
 
            </group>

        </command-line>
    </module>

</seiscomp>
